<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An Account of the whole proceedings at the sessions holden at the Sessions-House in the Old-Baily, for the city of London, county of Middlesex, &amp;c. which began on the twelfth of this instant July, and ended the 16th of the same : giving a particular relation of the tryals of divers high-way-men, clippers, fellons, traytors, and conspirators, but more especially of the tryals of William, Lord Russel, Thomas Walcot, John Rouse, William Hone, who were tryed and found guilty for conspiring against the life of the King and endeavouring the subversion of the government, with the sentence pronounced gainst hem [sic] &amp;c.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1683</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 17 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A26228</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A423</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R6781</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12379897</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12379897</idno>
            <idno type="VID">60714</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A26228)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 60714)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 267:3)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An Account of the whole proceedings at the sessions holden at the Sessions-House in the Old-Baily, for the city of London, county of Middlesex, &amp;c. which began on the twelfth of this instant July, and ended the 16th of the same : giving a particular relation of the tryals of divers high-way-men, clippers, fellons, traytors, and conspirators, but more especially of the tryals of William, Lord Russel, Thomas Walcot, John Rouse, William Hone, who were tryed and found guilty for conspiring against the life of the King and endeavouring the subversion of the government, with the sentence pronounced gainst hem [sic] &amp;c.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Court of Oyer and Terminer and Gaol Delivery (London and Middlesex).</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>4 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Lang. Curtis,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1683.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>"Entered according to order"</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Advertisement on p. 4.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Russell, William, --  Lord, 1639-1683 --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term>Walcot, Thomas, d. 1683 --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term>Rouse, John, d. 1683 --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term>Hone, William, d. 1683 --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term>Trials (Treason) --  England.</term>
               <term>Trials (Robbery) --  England.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>Scott Lepisto</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>Scott Lepisto</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="account">
            <pb facs="tcp:60714:1"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:60714:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>AN ACCOUNT Of the Whole <hi>Proceedings at the Seſſions,</hi> Holden at the <hi>Seſſions-Houſe</hi> in the <hi>Old-Baily,</hi> for the City of <hi>London,</hi> County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>Which began on the twelfth of this Inſtant</hi> July, <hi>and ended the 16th: of the ſame.</hi> Giving a Particular Relation of the Tryals of divers <hi>High-way-men, Clippers, Fellons, Traytors,</hi> and <hi>Conſpirators,</hi> but more eſpecially of the Tryals of
<list>
                  <item>
                     <hi>WILLIAM,</hi> Lord <hi>R<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>SSEL.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>THOMAS WALCOT.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>JOHN RO<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>SE.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>WILLIAM HONE.</hi>
                  </item>
               </list>
Who were Tryed, and found Guilty, for Conſpiring againſt the Life of the King, and endeavouring the Subver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion of the Government, with the Sentence pronounced gainſt hem, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Entered according to <hi>ORDER</hi>
            </head>
            <p>AT this Seſſions, beginning the day aboveſaid, Firſt in order, were Tryed <hi>Thomas Wilſon,</hi> and <hi>James Johnſon,</hi> upon three ſeveral Indictments; one for Robbing <abbr>Eſq</abbr> 
               <hi>Hide</hi> of <hi>Highgate</hi> on the Road, of divers Rings, Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, and other things, to the value of Eighty pound: Another for Robbing <hi>Robert Abel</hi> of a Watch, Rings, Money, a Coat, and other Things: And the laſt for Murthering one <hi>George Evans.</hi> The Evidence upon the Tryal, Swore to both the Indictments upon the Robbery, that the Priſoners were the Men that Robbed the Perſons aforeſaid, and that upon Search, the Buttons of the Coat, taken at that time, was found in <hi>Johnſon</hi>'s Lodging: As to the Murther, it appeared to be thus. The Townſmen of <hi>Iſlington</hi> having notice of the Robbe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries committed that way, layed the Ways, and in a ſhort time met the Priſoners, whom they ſuſpecting to be the Robbers, commanded them to ſurrender them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, which they refuſed, endeavouring to eſcape, and <hi>Johnſon</hi> finding himſelf hardly purſued, he with a Piſtol ſhot <hi>Evans,</hi> the Perſon that purſued him, of which Wound the next day he died: The Priſoners Pleaded Innocence as to the Robbery, but not being able to give any good Account of themſelves they were upon full Evidence found Guilty.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:60714:2"/>
            <p>
               <hi>John Mugleſtone, Roger Mugleſtone,</hi> and <hi>John Harris,</hi> were tryed for Clipping the Currant Coine of this Kingdom, as <hi>Elizabeth, James,</hi> and <hi>Charles</hi> the <hi>Firſt, Halfe-Crowns, Shillings,</hi> &amp;c. The Evidence was, that the former of the Priſoners had at divers times been ſeen to Clip and File Money, and that he ſent a Youth to ſell divers quantities of melted Silver, with one of which Parcels being ſeized by the <hi>Goldſmith</hi> to whom he offered it, he confeſſed where he had it, upon which the Priſoners Houſe was ſearched, where divers Shears, Melting-Pots, Files, and other ſuch like Inſtruments were found: As alſo, a conſiderable quantity of Clipped Money: As to the Second Perſon he was Brother to the former, and aſſiſting to him in his Defrauding Occupation: And againſt <hi>Harris</hi> it was Sworn, that he furniſhed the Priſoners with Money, and had Six-pence in the Pound for Clipping, and that he had of a long time been of Confederacy with them; upon which, and ſundry other Circumſtances, as the Inſtruments being produced in Court, and the Bars of Melted Silver, and the like, the Jury found them all three guilty of the <hi>High-Treaſon,</hi> as in the <hi>Indictment</hi> layed.</p>
            <p>This Seſſions <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Ruſſel,</hi> was Tryed upon an Indictment for <hi>High-Treaſon,</hi> for deſigning to Leavy War, and compaſs the Death of His Majeſty. The Evidence againſt him was the Lord <hi>Howard,</hi> Collonel <hi>Shepherd</hi> a Vintner in <hi>Corn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hill,</hi> &amp;c. who Depoſed, that he had been at divers Conſults in order to raiſe Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bellion and Leavy War, and a General Riſing throughout the Kingdom, and that a Declaration had been drawn to that purpoſe, and a Survey taken of the King's Guards at the <hi>Savoy</hi> and <hi>Muſe,</hi> in order to Surprize them, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> So that after divers Arguments the Jury found him Guilty of the <hi>High-Treaſon.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Thomas Wallcot, John Rouſe, William Hone,</hi> and <hi>William Blake,</hi> were Tryed for Conſpiring againſt the Life of the King, and deſigning to Subvert the Government, and make a miſerable Slaughter amongſt the King's Subjects as to the three former it plainly appeared, that they had been in divers Conſults about Killing the King and Duke in their Return from <hi>New-Market,</hi> that it was abſolutely concluded, and Arms for that purpoſe prepared, but that the Fire occaſioning the King's ſudden remove prevented it againſt the later. Evidence was given that he was to raiſe a pow'r of Seamen to ſeize on the Tower, and for that purpoſe had prepared Shipping to batter it from off the Water, and that divers Diſcourſes tending thereto had been by him uttered, but the main ſtreſs as to <hi>Blake,</hi> reſted upon one Evidence only, whereupon after Charge given, the Jury found the three former Guilty of <hi>High-Treaſon,</hi> and Acquitted the later.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Ruſſel, Thomas Wallcot, John Rouſe,</hi> and <hi>William Hone,</hi> being Convicted as aboveſaid, the King's Attorney General prayed Judgment againſt them, whereupon they were brought to the Bar, and asked what they had to ſay why Judgment ſhould not be awarded againſt them, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> whereupon the <hi>Lord Ruſſel</hi> deſired to hear the Indictment read, which was allowed, and then made ſome Objections, that there was no proof againſt him of his actual deſigning to kill the King, only for Conſpiring to Leavy War, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> but he was told that the Ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict was paſſed, and it now remained the Duty of the Court to paſs Sentence. <hi>Hone, Wallcot,</hi> and <hi>Rouſe,</hi> being asked what they could ſay, deſired that their Friends might have liberty to ſee them, and time to prepare for another World. Then Sentence was paſſed, as followeth, <hi>viz.</hi> That <hi>they ſhould return to the place from whence they came, from thence be drawn to the Common place of Execution upon Hurdles, and there to be Hanged by the Necks, then cut down alive, their Privy-Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers cut off, and Bowels taken out to be burnt before their Faces, their Heads to be ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered from their Bodies, and their Bodies divided into four parts, to be diſpoſed of as the King ſhould think fit.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:60714:2"/>
            <p>
               <hi>William Knowles</hi> was Tryed, for that he the 20th of <hi>June</hi> broke open the houſe of <hi>Phillip Stubb</hi> in <hi>Cornhill,</hi> and took thence in Plate and Money, to the value of 50 pounds, which Robbery he before the Juſtice upon his being Apprehended, confeſſed to have thus effected, <hi>viz.</hi> That going up and finding the Key in the Chamber-door, he opened it, and broke open the Boxes with an Iron Skewer, and took out the Plate, Money, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſome of which Plate upon proffer to Sale was ſtopped, and he Apprehended. This and other Evidence given againſt him he was found Guilty of the Felony.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Francis Smith</hi> of St. <hi>Andrew</hi>'s <hi>Holburn,</hi> was Tryed upon an Indictment of <hi>High-Treaſon,</hi> for Clipping the Lawful Coin of this Kingdom, when by one Evidence it appeared that he had often with Shears and other Inſtruments Clipped, Filed, and Diminiſhed Half-Crowns, Shillings, Sixpences, and the like; but the other Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs not Swearing poſitive, but only by Circumſtances, the Priſoner was Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quitted.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Jane Dodſon</hi> an Old-woman, was Tryed for a Witch, it being Sworn againſt her, that ſhe uſed divers <hi>Helliſh Arts</hi> and <hi>Inchantations</hi> to deſtroy divers Perſons eſpecially that ſhe lamed and diſtorted by her Cunning in <hi>Witchcraft</hi> and <hi>Sorcery,</hi> one <hi>Mary Palmer,</hi> and killed another as the Evidence believed; but not making it appear what means ſhe uſed, or how the matter was brought about, and divers Perſons appearing to Teſtifie her Life and Converſation, ſhe was Acquitted.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>William Barret,</hi> and <hi>Elizabeth Attwell</hi> were indicted for Robbing one Mr. <hi>Cuttler</hi> of <hi>Hornzey</hi> of 100 pounds in money, which Robbery <hi>Barret</hi> confeſſed, and decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red that none but himſelf was concerned in the Robbery, whereupon the other was Acquitted.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>John Spittle</hi> and one <hi>Gratrick,</hi> took their Tryals for Robbing one Mr. <hi>Pitts</hi> near <hi>Mile-end</hi> on the 9th of <hi>May</hi> laſt of a Watch, four Pounds in Money, Rings, a Silver-handled Knife and Fork, the which being poſitively ſworn againſt them by reaſon the Party Robbed knew them at the time of the Robbery, and therefore had narrowly Eſcaped with Life, and they proved Notorious Offendors, the Jury found them Guilty.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Elizabeth Maſon</hi> of the Pariſh of <hi>St. Sepulchres,</hi> was Tryed for ſtealing a Coat valued at Twenty ſhillings, from <hi>Thomas Midwinter,</hi> but it appearing that ſhe had it of his Maid Servant ſhe was Acquitted.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Joſeph Brockly</hi> was Indicted for ſeveral Parcels of Goods from one Mr. <hi>Lowman,</hi> to which upon his Arraignment he Pleaded the old <hi>New-gate</hi> Plea, <hi>viz.</hi> Guilty of that and all other Felonies within the Benefit of his Clergy.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Richard Sinnel</hi> was Indicted for Marrying a ſecond Wife during the Life of his firſt Wife, to which Indictment he pleaded Guilty, owning the Fact, which by Law is Felony.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>John Plumpton</hi> was Tryed for Conveying away on the 10th of <hi>June</hi> divers pie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces of Plate from <hi>Edward Vile,</hi> who intruſted him therewith, but it appearing they were delivered into his Cuſtody, it was not Felony, whereupon he was Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quitted.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Francis Engliſh</hi> an In-keeper, was Tryed for taking a Mare from one Mr. <hi>Long</hi> upon the Road, which Mare was afterward found in his Stable, but he alledging ſhe was brought in by a ſtranger, who the next day promiſed to call for her, and bringing divers to Atteſt where he was at the time the Robbery was Committed, the Jury Acquitted him.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Margaret Nicolſon,</hi> was Tryed for Clipping the Lawful Coin of this Kingdom, as Shillings, Half-Crowns, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> which was firſt ſuſpected, as it was given in Evidence againſt her, by changing divers Clipped pieces of Money, and ſearching her houſe
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:60714:3"/>they found Files, Shears, and Rubbing-ſtones, which the Priſoner alledged were left there when ſhe came to the houſe, and there being no actual Clipping proved, ſhe was Acquitted.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Margaret Chamberlain</hi> was Tryed for ſtealing Knives, Canes, and Swords from one Mr. <hi>Warradine</hi> a Cutler, in St. <hi>Martin</hi>'s in the Fields, the proof againſt her was, that part of the Goods were found about her, and that ſhe had ſold the reſt in divers places, to which ſhe Pleaded that they were delivered to her by a Woman ſhe met in <hi>Holborn</hi> by chance, but not being able to prove it, ſhe was found Guilty.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>George Jones,</hi> was Arraigned for ſtealing 10 <abbr>
                  <hi>l.</hi>
               </abbr> in Money numbered, from <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Frind,</hi> upon plain proof of which he was Convicted of the Felony, as like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe was <hi>Joſeph Dumply</hi> for ſtealing goods to a conſiderable value from one <hi>John Roman. Jonathan Ball</hi> was likewiſe Tryed and found Guilty for Robbing <hi>John Croſs</hi> of five Pounds in Money.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>John South</hi> 
               <abbr>Eſq</abbr> took his Tryal for killing <hi>William Atkinſon</hi> in the Pariſh of St. <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drew</hi>'s <hi>Holborn,</hi> on the 26. of <hi>May</hi> laſt, the Manner thus. The Priſoner and the Deceaſed in the Paſſage of a Yard in <hi>Grays-Inn-Lane</hi> drew upon each other, and after a Paſs, cloſed, and then falling off again departed to their reſpective Habitati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, but the Deceaſed had firſt received a Wound in his Belly of which in a ſhort time he died; but no former Quarrel being proved, nor any Malicious Intent, the Priſoner was found Guilty of Man-ſlaughter only, and for ſtay of Burning in the hand, producing the King's Warrant, he was Diſmiſſed upon giving ſecurity to Appear the next Goal-Delivery: Bail was likewiſe taken for <hi>William Blake</hi> the Sea Captain, Tryed for <hi>High-Treaſon,</hi> and Acquitted as is aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Iſabel Simms</hi> was Tryed for Robbing <hi>John Brown</hi> of St. <hi>Martin</hi>'s, of a Silver Tankard, 3 Silver Spoons, a Silver Salt, a Cup, and divers other pieces of Plate, to the value of 24 pounds, which Robbery, as the Witneſſes depoſed, ſhe confeſſed ſome time after her being Apprehended, and that ſhe was in the houſe a little before the Robbery was Committed, to inquire for a Lodger, whereupon ſhe was found Guilty.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>John Knot</hi> was Tryed for ſtealing a Scarfe, a Hood, a Cornet, and other things from one Mr. <hi>Parſons</hi> on the third of <hi>May</hi> laſt, many of the things being afterward found where he had diſpoſed of them, upon which he was found Guilty.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Benjamin Cooper</hi> was Tryed for ſtealing a Silver Cup, a Silver Thimble, and other Plate to the value of 30 ſhillings from <hi>Samuel Wadcot</hi> of <hi>Holborn,</hi> on the 28 of <hi>May</hi> laſt, which Goods being proved to be taken upon him, he was found Guilty.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Joſeph Mills</hi> was Tryed for ſtealing Sheets, Plate, Money, Rings, and divers ſorts of wearing Linnen, to the value of 30 <abbr>
                  <hi>l.</hi>
               </abbr> from <hi>Jane Guttrell</hi> of the Pariſh of St. <hi>Martin</hi>'s in the Fields on the 26 of <hi>June</hi> laſt; the Evidence given againſt him was, that upon ſearch, a Purſe with divers Rings, owned by the Proſecutors, was found between the Bed and Mat in his Lodging Chamber, but there being no poſitive proof of the Felony, and he bringing divers to give the Court an account of his Life and Converſation, he was acquitted.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Mary Grifith</hi> was Tryed for ſtealing a ſilver Tankard from <hi>Anne Ray</hi> on the 22d. of <hi>May</hi> laſt, but the proof againſt her being weak, ſhe was acquitted.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anthony Sympſon</hi> was Indicted and Tryed for Killing one <hi>George Butler</hi> on the 26th. of <hi>May</hi> laſt; as likewiſe were <hi>John Scot</hi> and <hi>Samuel Godlygood,</hi> for killing <hi>Mary Edwards</hi> on the 30th of <hi>June</hi> laſt, but the Evidence being but Circumſtantial, and not Poſitive, they were all 3 acquitted.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Elizabeth Hall</hi> was Tryed for ſtealing a Scarfe, an Apron, and divers other wearing Apparrel from <hi>Henry Taylor</hi> of <hi>Alderſgate</hi> Pariſh, but the proof againſt her being deficient, ſhe was acquitted.</p>
            <p>On <hi>Saturday</hi> the <hi>Grand Jury</hi> delivered an Adreſs in order to its being preſented to His Majeſty, expreſſing therein the Joy they conceive for the Preſervation of His Majeſties Sacred Perſon, and their juſt deteſtation and abhorrence of the deteſtable Conſpiracy lately carried on to Depoſe and Murther him and to Subvert the <hi>Government, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This Seſſions, <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Ruſſel, Thomas Walcot, John Rouſe</hi> and <hi>William Hone,</hi> recived Sen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence for <hi>High-Treaſon</hi> as Conſpirators, <hi>John Muggleſtone, John Harris,</hi> and <hi>Roger Muggleſton,</hi> were likewiſe Sentenced for High-Treaſon for <hi>Clipping</hi> and <hi>Defacing the</hi> Currant Coin <hi>of this</hi> Kingdom, <hi>Thomas Wilſon, Miles Johnſon, John Spittle, William Gratrix, Mary Chamberlaine,</hi> and <hi>Elizabeth Simmes,</hi> were Sentenced for divers <hi>Robberies</hi> and <hi>Fellonies,</hi> theſe for <hi>Treaſon</hi> to be <hi>Drawn, Hang'd,</hi> and <hi>Quartered,</hi> and the others to be hanged only,</p>
            <p>
               <hi>George Jones, Richard, Simnel, Jonathan Ball,</hi> and <hi>Benjamin Cooper,</hi> were Burnt in the hand, <hi>John Knot, Will. Knowles, Joſeph Drumply,</hi> and <hi>Thomas Barret</hi> ordered for <hi>Tranſportation,</hi> and ſo ended this Remarkable Seſſions.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="notice">
            <head>Advertiſement.</head>
            <p>THeſe are to give notice that notwithſtanding a ſhort Account of the Tryals of <hi>William</hi> Lord <hi>Ruſſel, Thomas Walcot, William Hone, John Rouſe,</hi> and <hi>William Blake,</hi> that are given in this and other Papers, Publiſhed by the Publiſher hereof, that the Tryal at large will be ſhortly Publiſhed by <hi>Richard Chiſwel</hi> at the <hi>Role</hi> and <hi>Crown</hi> in St. <hi>Paul</hi>'s Church-yard.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON.</hi> Printed for <hi>Lang. Curtis,</hi> 1683.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:60714:3"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
